Donald Hyde and Mary Hyde Eccles Autograph Collection (MS Hyde 10): Guide.
Donald Hyde and Mary Hyde Eccles Autograph Collection,
- Defoe, Daniel, 1661?-1731. Autograph letter, signed, Newington near Hackney [London] to Thomas Wharton, Marquess of Wharton, 1710 Apr. 7., (180); 4s.
  Advises against support for a disgraced clergyman named Cooper from Leeds (England). With typed transcript.
- Denman, Thomas Denman, Baron, 1779-1854. Autograph letter, signed, Portland Place [London] to Sir Anthony Panizzi, 1841 Nov. 14., (181); 1s.
  Letter of introduction for relative John Doe Denman.
- Derby, Edward Smith Stanley, Earl of, 1752-1834. Autograph letter, signed, Grosvenor Square [London] to William Windham, 1797 Jan. 22., (182); 1s.
  Concerning Lancashire militia matters.
- Devonshire, Georgiana Spencer Cavendish, Duchess of, 1757-1806. Autograph note, [no place] to Mr. Fosbroock, [17--?], (183); 1s.
  Requesting theater tickets.
- Devonshire, Georgiana Spencer Cavendish, Duchess of, 1757-1806. Autograph note, signed, [no place] to [Aaron] Graham, 1801 July 16., (184); 1s.
  Will visit later in the summer.
- Disraeli, Isaac, 1766-1848. Autograph letter, signed, Athenaeum Club (London, England), to A. (Abraham) Hayward, [1835] Jan. 23 Friday., (185); 2s.
  Concerning the popular interest in legal history, and other literary matters. With cover.
- Disraeli, Isaac, 1766-1848. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to Thomas Hill (1760-1840), [18--?] Monday., (186); 1s.
  Concerning the loan of a book, and a theater ticket.
  Partial transcript in Adam, 186.
- Dixie, Beaumont, 1629-1692. Discharge: document, signed, [no place] 1688 Apr. 20., (187); 1s.
  Quitclaim to Lady Frances Noell, widow of Sutton Cheney. Witnessed by Thomas Dixie and C. Cappur.
- Dodd, William, 1729-1777. Autograph note, [London] to John Hodgson [Secretary to John Green, Bishop of Lincoln] [1777 June 23], (188); 2s.
  Requests a visit at the prison, four days before Dodd's execution. On verso, autograph note, signed, by John's brother Hugh Hodgson, 1799 Nov. 6, explaining that Dodd was attempting to rally the bishops on his behalf. With a separate explanatory note, signed, by W. Hodgson, grandson of Hugh Hodgson.
- Dodd, William, 1729-1777. Autograph letter, signed, Plastow [England] to John Parkhurst, 1757 July 20., (189); 1s.
  Sends a fair copy of Dodd's translation of The Prayer of Orpheus to Museus (included).
- Dodd, William, 1729-1777. Copy of Dr. Dodd's speech to the Recorder of London after receiving sentence of death: Manuscript transcript, [no place] 1777 May 16., (190); 2s.
  Transcript of Dodd's speech in response to his death sentence. Transcript and notes by Weeden Butler. In poor condition; split at folds.
  O.M. Brack, Jr., The Macaroni Parson and the Concentrated Mind (Tucson, Az.: The Johnsonians, 2004), 45-47.
- Dodsley, James, 1724-1797. Manuscript note, [no place] to Thomas Cadell, 1794 Dec. 10., (190a); 1s.
  Requests an account of The Adventurer.
  *2003JM-35
- Dodsley, James, 1724-1797. Autograph note, [no place] to Charlotte Lennox, 1793 Feb. 2., (191); 1s.
  Sends financial assistance, but denies legal responsibility for her claim concerning the books burned in his warehouse fire.
- Dodsley, James, 1724-1797. Autograph note, signed, [no place] to J. (John) Nourse, 1768 Dec. 21., (191a); 1s.
  Order for a book.
- Dodsley, Robert, 1703-1764. Receipt: manuscript document, [no place] 1751 Jan. 16., (192); 1s.
  Receipt to Mr. Adair for books purchased, signed by George Knapp for Dodsley.
- Dorset, John Frederick Sackville, Duke of, 1745-1799. Letter, signed, Dorset House [London] to William Windham, 1797 Apr. 15., (193); 1s.
  Sends a summary of the militia strength of the County of Kent (England).
- Douglas, John, 1721-1807. Autograph letter, signed, Windsor Castle [Berkshire, England] to [Andrew?] Millar, 1768 July 4., (194); 1s.
  Concerning personal finances.
- Douglass, George. Autograph letter, signed, Inchmarlo [Aberdeenshire, Scotland] to James Skene, [1796] Oct. 16., (195); 1s.
  Humorous letter, asking Skene to forgive "Bozzy" (James Boswell?) for his comments on Germans.
- Dunbar, James, d. 1798. 2 autograph letters, signed, King's College, Aberdeen (Scotland), to [William Strahan] 1782-1783., (196); 2s.
  Concerning publication plans, Chinese grammar, and forthcoming trips to London.
- Dunning, John, Baron Ashburton, 1731-1783. Autograph note, Temple [London] to Mr. Way of Lincoln's Inn Fields [London] [not before 1758] Sunday., (197); 1s.
  Requests a copy of a 1758 act of the assembly concerning Jamaica.
- Duppa, Richard, 1770-1831. Autograph letter, signed, 13 Poland Street [London] to Sir Joseph Banks, 1804 Dec. 11., (198); 1s.
  Comments on the rejection of his application to the Royal Society.
- Duppa, Richard, 1770-1831. Autograph letter, signed, Newman Street [London] to [Anthony] Molteno, 1796 June 7., (199); 1s.
  Offers prints for display in Molteno's shop.
- Dyer, Charles George. Autograph letter, signed, Old Ford [London?] to George Jones, 1836 Jan. 7., (200); 1s.
  Sends a print of the attempted murder of Mary Nicol by John Elliot (1747-1787), and discusses Nicol at length. Mounted on a sheet with An Address Written by Mr. Charles Dyer, a printed broadside poem, 1820 Apr. 10.
- Edwards, Edward, ca. 1726-1783. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to Sir Robert Chambers, 1782 Feb. 2., (201); 1s.
  Mostly concerning University of Oxford matters. Discusses Samuel Johnson's health and opinions of Edwards's work.
- Edwards, Jonathan, 1703-1758. Autograph letter, signed, Stockbridge (Mass.), to William Hogg, 1755 Dec. 11., (202); 1s.
  Concerning publication plans. One corner missing, with some loss of text.
- Eglinton, Hugh Montgomerie, Earl of, 1739-1819. Autograph letter, signed, Eglinton Castle [Ayrshire, Scotland] to unidentified recipient, 1808 Apr. 19., (203); 1s.
  Reports that the Eglinton family paintings were all lost in a fire.
- Eldon, John Scott, Earl of, 1751-1838. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to George Pretyman (then Bishop of Winchester), 1822 June 1., (204); 1s.
- Eldon, John Scott, Earl of, 1751-1838. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to unidentified recipient, [not before 1801], (205); 1s.
  Concerning application of the Great Seal in Eldon's role as Lord Chancellor.
- Elgin, Thomas Bruce, Earl of, 1766-1841. Autograph letter, signed, Coblence [Koblenz, Germany] to unidentified recipient, 1793 Apr. 2., (206); 1s.
  Describes the movements of the Prussian military.
- Ellis, Henry, Sir, 1777-1869. Autograph letter, signed, British Museum [London] to William Bernard Cooke, 1824 July 15., (207); 1s.
  Concerning Cooke's request to engrave items from the British Museum.
- Ellis, Henry, Sir, 1777-1869. Autograph letter, signed, British Museum [London] to John Gough Nichols, 1854 June 3., (208); 1s.
  Sends part of an article from the forthcoming Archaeologia.
- Elmsley, Peter, 1734 or 5-1802. Autograph letter, signed, Leiden (Netherlands), to [J. (John)] Nourse, 1775 Oct. 24., (209); 1s.
  Concerning efforts to print a liturgy.
- England and Wales. Privy Council. Order: manuscript document, signed, Greenwich (London, England), 1600 Apr. 30., (210); 1s.
  Order to the commissioners of the muster for Norfolk (England) to send an account of their troops. Signed by twelve members of the privy council of Elizabeth I, Queen of England:; John Whitgift (then Archbishop of Canterbury); Sir Thomas Egerton;; Thomas Sackville, Earl of Dorset (then Baron Buckhurst); Charles Howard, Earl of Nottingham;; Gilbert Talbot, Earl of Shrewsbury;; Edward Somerset, Earl of Worcester;; William Knollys, Earl of Banbury;; John Stanhope;; Robert Cecil, Earl of Salisbury;; J. Fortescu;; Sir John Popham; and Sir John Herbert.
- England and Wales. Privy Council. Letter, signed, York House [London] to unidentified recipient, 1616 Sept. 4., (211); 1s.
  Fragment of a letter signed jointly by Francis Bacon (1561-1626);; Sir Thomas Egerton (then Baron Ellesmere); Fulke Greville, Baron Brooke;; Sir Julius Caesar;; Edward Somerset, Earl of Worcester; and George Carew, Earl of Totnes.
- England and Wales. Privy Council. Order: manuscript document, signed, Whitehall [London] 1626 Nov. 30., (212); 1s.
  Order to the commissioners of the loans for the city of Coventry (England). Signed by fifteen members of the privy council of Charles I, King of England, including William Herbert, 3rd Earl of Pembroke;; Philip Herbert, Earl of Pembroke (then Earl of Montgomery); Theophilus Howard, Earl of Suffolk;; William Cecil, Earl of Salisbury;; William Cecil, Earl of Exeter;; John Egerton, Earl of Bridgewater;; Oliver St. John, Viscount Grandison of Limerick;; Edward Conway, Viscount Conway of Conway Castle;; Dudley Carleton, 1st Viscount Dorchester;; Sir Thomas Edmondes;; Sir John Suckling;; Sir John Coke;; Sir Julius Caesar; and others.
- Erskine, Thomas Erskine, Baron, 1750-1823. Autograph note, [no place] to Mr. Glynn, 1823 Sept. 21., (213); 1s.
  Requesting a copy of the Greek constitution.
- Erskine, Thomas Erskine, Baron, 1750-1823. Autograph letter, signed, [Sergeant's?] Inn [London] to John Jervis, Viscount St. Vincent, 1788 Jan. 26., (214); 1s.
  Reports on a legal case concerning Mr. Henry.
- Estienne, Henri, 1531-1598. Nescio qua natale solum: autograph manuscript, signed, [no place] 1575 June., (215); 1s.
  Eleven lines in Latin and Greek, quoting Ovid. On verso, autograph lines in Latin, signed by Johannes Haller and Abraham Muscatus [?]
- Faulder, Robert, 1747 or 8-1815. Autograph letter, signed, Ramsgate (England), to General [Sir Herbert?] Taylor, 1813 July 27., (216); 1s.
  Concerning Taylor's magazine order.
- Faulkner, George, 1699?-1775. Autograph letter, signed, Dublin (Ireland), to unidentified recipient, 1763 Oct. 27., (217); 1s.
  Concerning delivery of a parcel of books for John Lockman.
- Fawcett, Owen, 1838-1904. Autograph note, signed, [no place] to [E.H. (Edward Hugh)?] Sothern, 1898 Dec. 30., (218); 1s.
  Presentation letter, found in an 1805 edition of The Thespian Dictionary.
- Ferguson, [Adam,] 1723-1816. Autograph note, [Edinburgh, Scotland] to Bell Bradfute, 1805 Dec. 25., (219); 1s.
  Requesting a book.
- Ferguson, James, 1710-1776. A magic square by Dr. Franklin: autograph manuscript, [no place] [1767?], (220); 1s.
  Demonstration of a mathematical curiosity created by Benjamin Franklin.
  The same magic square was published in Leonard W. Labaree, ed., Papers of Benjamin Franklin (New Haven: Yale University Press, 1961), 4:395, from a different manuscript with alternate text.
- Ferguson, James, 1710-1776. Receipt: autograph document, signed, [no place] 1757 July 20., (221); 1s.
  Receipt to J. (John) Nourse for astronomy books. Mounted with an uncredited portrait etching of Ferguson.
- Fielding, Henry, 1707-1754. By 34 E3(a) justices of the peace: autograph manuscript, [no place] [17--], (222); 1s.
  Legal manuscript fragment concerning justices of the peace. On verso, autograph manuscript authentication, signed by grandson William Henry Fielding, 1828 Feb.
  Hugh Amory, "A Preliminary Census of Henry Fielding's Legal Manuscripts," The Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America, 62:4 (1968), 587-601, item 8.
- Fielding, Henry, 1707-1754. Causing chapters and congregations: autograph manuscript, [no place] [17--], (223); 1s.
  Legal manuscript fragment concerning a case of unlawful assembly. Autograph manuscript authentication, signed, by grandson William Henry Fielding. With an attached autograph manuscript presentation note, signed by Sir Bernard Burke.
  Hugh Amory, "A Preliminary Census of Henry Fielding's Legal Manuscripts," The Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America, 62:4 (1968), 587-601, item 11.
- Fielding, Henry, 1707-1754. Deserves a privilege: autograph manuscript, [no place] [17--], (224); 2s.
  Legal manuscript fragment concerning the regulation of monopolies. On verso, autograph manuscript authentication, signed, by grandson William Henry Fielding, 1828 Feb. Central fold taped on verso. With typescript transcript.
  Hugh Amory, "A Preliminary Census of Henry Fielding's Legal Manuscripts," The Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America, 62:4 (1968), 587-601, item 9.
- Fielding, Henry, 1707-1754. In an appeal w'ch is a civil ac'on: autograph manuscript, [no place] [17--], (225); 1s.
  Legal manuscript fragment concerning the right of defendant to enter a plea. With autograph manuscript authentication, signed by grandson William Henry Fielding, 1826 July 22.
  Hugh Amory, "A Preliminary Census of Henry Fielding's Legal Manuscripts," The Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America, 62:4 (1968), 587-601, item 5.
- Fielding, Henry, 1707-1754. That the king can pardon all offences: autograph manuscript, [no place] [17--], (226); 1s.
  Legal manuscript fragment concerning royal pardons. With autograph manuscript authentication, signed by grandson William Henry Fielding, Chelsea, 1832 Sept.
  Hugh Amory, "A Preliminary Census of Henry Fielding's Legal Manuscripts," The Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America, 62:4 (1968), 587-601, item 10.
- Fielding, John, Sir, 1721-1780. Note, signed, [no place] to Andrew Millar, 1764 Nov. 8., (227); 1s.
  Ordering a copy of his Extracts from Such of the Penal Laws.
- Fielding, John, Sir, 1721-1780. Letter, signed, [no place] to [John Wilkes] (then Lord Mayor of London), 1775 Apr. 9., (228); 1s.
  Opposes Wilkes's rumored plans for public demonstration against King George III's American policy. A related newspaper clipping is attached.
- Fife, James Duff, Earl of, 1729-1809. Autograph letter, signed, Whitehall (London), to unidentified recipient, 1789 Feb. 28., (229); 1s.
  Correcting a printer's error; also comments on the recovery of George III, King of Great Britain.
- Fitzgerald, William Thomas, 1759?-1829. Hint for an inscription to the memory of Johnson, and Garrick: autograph manuscript, signed, [no place] [17--?], (230); 1s.
  A poem in honor of Samuel Johnson and David Garrick.
  Partial transcript in Adam, 96-97.
- Forbes, James, 1749-1819. Behold this beauteous tree: autograph manuscript, signed, Stanmore Hill [London] 1798 May 19., (231); 1s.
  Poem dedicated to his niece Elizabeth Fothergill, apparently written as a presentation inscription for a book.
- Forbes, William, Sir, 1739-1806. Autograph letter, signed, Edinburgh (Scotland), to Sir Alexander Boswell, 1795 May 25., (232); 1s.
  Condolences on the death of James Boswell.
- Forbes, William, Sir, 1739-1806. Autograph letter, signed, Edinburgh (Scotland), to Edmond Malone, 1796 June 30., (233); 3s.
  Discusses the James Boswell papers at Auchinleck, the William Ireland Shakespeare forgeries, Samuel Johnson's opinion of Sir Joshua Reynolds, and other topics.
  Quoted in David Buchanan, The Treasure of Auchinleck (New York: McGraw-Hill, 1974), 3, 14, 188. Transcript in Adam, 98-100.
- Forbes, William, Sir, 1739-1806. Autograph letter, signed, Edinburgh (Scotland), to John Spottiswoode, 1778 Feb. 16., (234); 1s.
  Concerning the appointment of trustees at a chapel in Edinburgh.
- Forrester, James, d. 1765. Autograph letter, signed, Mary Bone [Marylebone, London] to Mr. Cockburn, 1764 Mar. 29., (235); 1s.
  Refers to Samuel Johnson's The Vanity of Human Wishes.
- Forster, Benjamin Meggot, 1764-1829. Names of several persons concerned in the affair of Elizabeth Canning and Mary Squires in 1753 and 1754: manuscript, Walthamstow [Essex] 1826 July 3., (236); 2 leaves, sewn.
  List compiled by Forster, although possibly not in his hand, as preparation for an investigation into the historical controversy over convicted perjurer Elizabeth Canning.
- Forster, George, d. 1792. Receipt: autograph document, signed, London, 1777 Sept. 23., (237); 1s.
  Receipt to George Robinson for rights to Forster's A Voyage Round the World.
- Foster, John, 1731-1774. Autograph letter, signed, Eton (England), to unidentified recipient, 1766 July 1., (238); 1s.
  Concerning Jeremiah Markland and a translation of Euripedes.
- Foulis, Robert, 1707-1776; and Foulis, Andrew, d. 1775. Autograph letter, signed, Glasgow (Scotland), to Thomas Becket, 1765 Nov. 26., (239); 1s.
  Concerning bookselling accounts. From the Sir Thomas Phillipps collection, marked as MS 13809.
- Foulis, Robert, 1707-1776; and Foulis, Andrew, d. 1775. 2 autograph letters, signed, Glasgow (Scotland), to J. (John) Nourse, 1755., (240); 2s.
  Concerning bookselling affairs, including lists of books ordered.
- Fox, Charles James, 1749-1806. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to unidentified recipient, [1783 Dec. 11] Thursday., (241); 2s.
  Reporting on a dispute between George III, King of Great Britain, and George Nugent Temple Grenville, Marquess of Buckingham (then Earl of Temple). With a manuscript extract in an unknown hand from the Annual Register, providing background on the dispute.
- Fox, Charles James, 1749-1806. Autograph letter, signed, St. Anne's Hill [Surrey, England] to unidentified recipient, [between 1784-1806] Monday., (242); 1s.
  Concerning an appointment certificate.
- Francklin, Thomas, 1721-1784. Receipt: document, signed, London, 1774 Mar. 15., (243); 1s.
  Receipt to Henry Hoare for a book subscription.
- Francklin, Thomas, 1721-1784. Receipt: document, signed, [no place] 1774 Dec., (244); 1s.
  Receipt to George Steevens for a book subscription.
- Frederick [II, King of Prussia, 1712-1786?] Letter, signed, Potsdam (Germany), to Sir Thomas Musgrave, 1785 Sept. 1., (245); 2s.
  Invites Musgrave to attend maneuvers. With cover panel.
- Frederick William I, King of Prussia, 1688-1740. Document, signed, Berlin (Germany), 1722 June 30., (246); 1s.
  In German.
- Fréron, Stanislas, 1754-1802. Autograph letter, signed, Marseille (France), to [Antoine-Christophe?] Saliceti, [1794 Jan. 12], (247); 1s.
  Letter of recommendation. In French.
- Gainsborough, Thomas, 1727-1788. Autograph letter, signed, Bath (England), to William Dodd, 1773 Nov. 24., (248); 1s.
  Comments on his portrait of Dodd.
  Published from a partial transcript in John Hayes, ed., The Letters of Thomas Gainsborough (New Haven, Ct.: Yale University Press, 2001), 120-122.
- Garrick, Eva Maria, 1724-1822. autograph note, [no place] to Robert Adam, [1777 Aug. 21] Thursday., (249); 1s.
  Inquires about Adam's construction schedule.
- Garrick, Eva Maria, 1724-1822. Autograph letter, signed, Adelphi [London] to Mrs. Blunt of Charlotte Street, London, [1817 Aug. 28] Thursday., (250); 1s.
  Concerning dinner plans.
- Garrick, Eva Maria, 1724-1822. Autograph letter, signed, Adelphi [London] to [Merrial Garrick Docksey] 1796 May 31., (251); 1s.
  Lamenting her late husband David Garrick.
- Garth, Samuel, Sir, 1661-1719. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to unidentified recipient, [17--?], (252); 1s.
  Offers thanks for comments.
- Garth, Samuel, Sir, 1661-1719. Receipt: document, signed, [no place] 1708 Oct. 20., (253); 1s.
  Receipt for annuity, made out to teller Thomas Townshend for His Majesty's Exchequer.
- Gatehouse, William. Receipt: manuscript document, London, 1821 May 22., (254); 1s.
  Receipt to Mr. Harris from W.D. Sole as executor of the estate of William Gatehouse.
- George I, King of Great Britain, 1660-1727. Passport: document, signed, St. James's Palace [London] 1720 Mar. 8., (255); 1s.
  Passport for Thomas Wentworth, Earl of Strafford, also signed by James Stanhope, Earl Stanhope. On vellum.
- George III, King of Great Britain, 1738-1820. Autograph letter, signed, St. James's Palace [London] to [Louis Joseph de Bourbon] prince de Condé, 1765 Nov. 4., (256); 1s.
  Announcing death of his uncle William Augustus, Duke of Cumberland. In French, with two seals. On the second page, manuscript English translation in an unknown hand.
- George III, King of Great Britain, 1738-1820. Commission: document, signed, Saville House [London?] 1760 Oct. 27., (257); 1s.
  Appointment of Henry Sanger as adjutant, also signed by William Pitt, Earl of Chatham. On vellum.
- George III, King of Great Britain, 1738-1820. Order to pay: document, signed, St. James's Palace [London] 1782 June 28., (258); 1s.
  Order to pay Frederick, Prince of Waldeck, for troops supplied for America. Also signed by Lord John Cavendish;; George John Spencer, Earl Spencer (then Viscount Althorp); and J. Grenville.
- George III, King of Great Britain, 1738-1820. Order to pay: document, signed, St. James's Palace [London] 1791 Apr. 20., (259); 1s.
  Order to pay Capt. William Anne John Crawley, also signed by Sir George Yonge. Brittle with some loss of text.
- Gerard, Alexander, 1728-1795. 2 autograph letters, signed, King's College, Aberdeen (Scotland), to William Strahan, 1777 Jan. 23., (260); 2s.
  The 1777 Jan. 23 letter concerns a politically sensitive manuscript. The 1778 Mar. 20 letter concerns the publication of a sermon.
- Gibbon, Edward, 1737-1794. Autograph letter, signed, Turk's Head, Gerard Street [London] to [Edmond Malone] 1782 Feb. 5., (261); 1s.
  Notifies Malone of his election to the Literary Club.
- Gibbon, Edward, 1737-1794. Autograph letter, signed, St. James's Street [London] to John Pinkerton, 1793 Nov. 23., (262); 1s.
  Arranges an appointment.
  Partial transcript in Adam, 108.
- Gibbon, Edward, 1737-1794. Note on Roman history: autograph manuscript, [no place] [17--], (263); 1s.
  Reads in its entirety, "AD 310, Trebellius Pollio - inter scriptores hist Augusta." Written on the verso of a playing card, with a manuscript endorsement dated 1832 in unknown hand.
- Gilpin, [William, 1724-1804?] Autograph note, "V.H." [England?] to Mr. White of Lymington (England), 1801 Jan. 24., (264); 1s.
  Discusses an anonymous dialogue believed to be by Hannah More.
- Gisborne, Thomas, 1794-1852. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to unidentified recipient, 1818 Mar. 27., (265); 1s.
  Concerning a purchase of land for the curacy of Barton [Staffordshire, England]
- Godwin, William, 1756-1836. Receipt: autograph document, signed, [no place] 1795 Nov. 21., (266); 1s.
  Receipt to George Robinson Co. for copyright to his The Adventures of Caleb Williams.
- Gordon, Charles George, 1833-1885. Autograph letter, signed, Cairo (Egypt), to Mr. Jansen, 1878 Mar. 13., (267); 1s.
  Gives orders concerning the administration of Sudan.
- Grafton, Augustus Henry Fitzroy, Duke of, 1735-1811. Autograph letter, signed, Euston [Suffolk, England] to unidentified recipient, 1781 Mar. 28., (268); 1s.
  Solicits an opinion on an admiralty matter.
- Grant, Archibald, Sir, 1696-1778. Autograph letter, signed, Pall Mall [London] to William Strahan, 1778 June 2., (269); 1s.
  Concerning an argument between Strahan and Grant's wife Jane Millar Grant.
- Graves, Richard, 1763-1829. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to unidentified recipient, 1803 Nov. 1., (270); 1s.
  Apologizes for delay in response.
- Great Britain. Parliament. House of Lords. Protest: manuscript transcript, [London] [1766 Mar.], (271); 4s., mounted together.
  Protest against the repeal of the Stamp Act, supported by 33 members of the House of Lords. Bound with a summary of the parliamentary proceedings for the debate on this issue. Transcript in unknown hand.
  James E. Thorold Rogers, A Complete Collection of the Protests of the Lords (Oxford: Clarendon Press, 1875) II, 76-84.
- Greene, Richard, 1716-1793. Autograph letter, signed, Lichfield (England), to [Richard Gough] 1786 Dec. 3., (272); 1s.
  Concerning a Lichfield artist named Stringer.
- Greville, Charles, 1794-1865. Autograph letter, signed, Council Office, Whitehall (London), to John Salusbury Piozzi Salusbury, 1837 Jan. 10., (273); 1s.
  Concerning Salusbury's resignation from his sheriff's office.
- Greville, Charles, 1794-1865. Autograph letter, signed, Newmarket (England), to unidentified recipient, [18--], (274); 1s.
  Concerning a speech by Adolphe Thiers, and funding for the British Museum.